<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Common Ground 2025</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Common Ground 2025</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 17:05:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Speakers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 17:05:22 -0500</pubDate><author>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/friday/</guid>
      <description>Ramon Rescindez 1:30pm Location: Franklin Hall, Room 310
Dr. Ramón Resendiz is a Chicanx documentary filmmaker and media anthropologist from the south Texas, U.S.-Mexico borderlands. He is a Postdoctoral Fellow at the Center for Research on Race and Ethnicity in Society and a Visiting Assistant Professor in the Media School at Indiana University. His research interrogates the material and imaginary intersections of national borders, memory, visual culture, systemic violence, and settler colonialism</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="ramon-rescindez">Ramon Rescindez</h2>
<p><strong>1:30pm Location: Franklin Hall, Room 310</strong></p>
<p>Dr. Ramón Resendiz is a Chicanx documentary filmmaker and media anthropologist from the south Texas, U.S.-Mexico borderlands. He is a Postdoctoral Fellow at the Center for Research on Race and Ethnicity in Society and a Visiting Assistant Professor in the Media School at Indiana University. His research interrogates the material and imaginary intersections of national borders, memory, visual culture, systemic violence, and settler colonialism</p>
<h2 id="cory-doctorow">Cory Doctorow</h2>
<p><strong>4pm, Location: Franklin Hall, Room 310</strong> or <a href="https://iu.zoom.us/meeting/register/Potbwk7eTlyoeYwaZRr7rw">Link to zoom here</a></p>
<p>Science fiction author, digital rights activist, and journalist Cory Doctorow will keynote the Media School Graduate Association’s Common Ground conference, presenting on his concept of “enshittification.”</p>
<p>Coined the “2023 Digital Word of the Year,” enshittification describes the process by which internet media platforms become simultaneously unusable and un-quittable.</p>
<p>Enshittification swept through the digital world over the past decade, and it has only accelerated since, as everything - grocery stores, nursing agencies, even public schools - became digital services. The more digital something is, the more vulnerable it is to enshittification.</p>
<p>Enshittification isn’t a force of nature. It’s not a historic inevitability. It’s the eminently foreseeable result of specific policy choices made by named individuals in living memory, after these individuals were warned that enshittification would ensue. Enshittification was a choice, not an accident.</p>
<p>The choices that led to enshittification are not graven in stone. They are just that - <em>choices</em>. We can choose otherwise. Indeed, we <em>must</em>, if we are to have an internet that is fit for purpose and can serve as the digital nervous system that we can use to coordinate our survival in a 21st century beset by genocide, ecological collapse, and economic chaos.</p>
<p>What policy choices can we make? What path can get us to those choices? How do we end the enshittocene and build a new, good internet?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Ground 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/screenings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/screenings/</guid>
      <description>this will be the film screening list</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>this will be the film screening list</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Panels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/saturday/</guid>
      <description>Panel 1 - Media Meets Geography 9am FH 310 Anna Stamm Staying Afloat: TV Station Marketing Strategies &amp;mdash; (Indiana University, Bloomington) Drew H. Using GIS to Stretch Archival Collections: A Case Study from Colorado &amp;mdash; (Indiana University, Bloomington) Feng Yi Yin	Linguistic Politics, Hybridity, and Localization: The Making of Transnational Indigenous African Language Television &amp;mdash; (Temple University) Abu Mohammad Sakil Faizullah Exploring Bluetooth Adoption Among Marginalized Rural Young Adults in Bangladesh: A Study from the Margins &amp;mdash; (Univerity of Georgia, Atlanta) Panel 2- Media Practices &amp;amp; Praxis 9am FH 210 Ran Wei The Paradox of Narrating from the Margins: the Self-representations of Kamagasaki in Amateur Media &amp;mdash; (Washington University in St.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="panel-1---media-meets-geography">Panel 1 - Media Meets Geography</h3>
<h4 id="9am-fh-310">9am FH 310</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Anna Stamm</strong>  <em>Staying Afloat: TV Station Marketing Strategies</em> &mdash;
(Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Drew H.</strong>   <em>Using GIS to Stretch Archival Collections: A Case Study from Colorado</em> &mdash;
(Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Feng Yi Yin</strong>	 <em>Linguistic Politics, Hybridity, and Localization: The Making of Transnational Indigenous African Language Television</em> &mdash;
(Temple University)</li>
<li><strong>Abu Mohammad Sakil Faizullah</strong> <em>Exploring Bluetooth Adoption Among Marginalized Rural Young Adults in Bangladesh: A Study from the Margins</em> &mdash;
(Univerity of Georgia, Atlanta)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-2--media-practices--praxis">Panel 2- Media Practices &amp; Praxis</h3>
<h4 id="9am-fh-210">9am FH 210</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ran Wei</strong> <em>The Paradox of Narrating from the Margins: the Self-representations of Kamagasaki in Amateur Media</em> &mdash;
(Washington University in St. Louis)</li>
<li><strong>Jenna Sears</strong> <em>Digital Creative Geographies: Intercultural Filmmaking as Affective Placemaking</em> &mdash;
(Indiana University)</li>
<li><strong>Julia longo</strong>	 <em>Journalistic documentaries as an emancipatory practice for adolescents: dialogues between communicative citizenship and media literacy</em> &mdash;
(Temple University)</li>
<li><strong>Narmeen Ijaz</strong> <em>Ethics in Feminist Documentary: Implications of Class and Privilege in Sharmeen Obaid-Chinoy’s Films</em> &mdash; (Indiana University, Bloomington)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-3--black-media-experiences">Panel 3- Black Media Experiences</h3>
<h4 id="1130am-fh-310">11:30am FH 310</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Marilyn Facey</strong> <em>New Media and Cultural Production: An examination of new media technologies on news and music production culture in Jamaica</em> (University of Illinois, Chicago)</li>
<li><strong>Kristin Wells</strong>  <em>Mediated Histories of Collegiate Sporting Protests: A Digital Humanities Approach</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Fabiola D&rsquo;Angelo</strong>	 <strong>Lovers Rock and The Black Sensorium</strong> (Indiana University)</li>
<li><strong>Omoleye Adeyemi</strong>	<em>The Shade Room—A Digital Third Space for Black Individuals</em> (Univeristy of Maryland College Park)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-4--structuring-environmental-feelings">Panel 4- Structuring Environmental Feelings</h3>
<h4 id="1130am-fh-210">11:30am FH 210</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Juntao Yang</strong>  <em>Fault Lines and Echoing Strata: Attunement and Unsecurement through East Asia’s Earthquake-Media</em> &mdash; (Columbia University)</li>
<li><strong>Stas</strong>  <em>Staging Apocalypse: Chornobyl Cinema, Environmental Protest, and Eschatological Melodrama</em> &mdash; (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Priscilla Boateng</strong>  <em>Navigating Motherhood and Mental Health in Ghana: A Critical Discourse Analysis of Postpartum Depression on Facebook</em> (Indiana University)</li>
<li><strong>Shitemi Khamadi</strong> <em>Media Representation of Indigenous Communities in Environmental Court Cases: A Feminist Critical Discourse Analysis of Landmark Judgments in Africa</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-5--fan-power">Panel 5- Fan Power</h3>
<h4 id="315pm-fh-310">3:15pm FH 310</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Juntong Wu</strong> <em>Mediating Film Festival in Post-Pandemic China: Cinephiles and Grassroots Media</em> (?)</li>
<li><strong>Selena Cotte</strong> <em>Video essays and fan historians as alternative academics: Considering Defunctland and other theme park studies.</em> (University of Illinois, Chicago)</li>
<li><strong>Aditya Sahasrabudhe</strong> <em>Investigating fan aggression as a reaction to mediated crowd behavior</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-6--rendering-media-visions">Panel 6- Rendering Media Visions</h3>
<h4 id="315pm-fh-210">3:15pm FH 210</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aileen Min</strong> <em>Digital Water and Generative Absence: Reimagining East Asian Aesthetics in Digital Art</em> (Columbia University)</li>
<li><strong>Ibrahim Odugbemi</strong> <em>Global South Cinemas in the Face of Neoliberal Capitalism: The Examples of Nigeria and South Korea</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Aanila	A</strong> (<em>Reassessment of the Aura: Analyzing the Categories of AI-generated Images in Facebook&rsquo;s Algorithmic Landscape</em> Indiana University)</li>
<li><strong>Janice Day</strong> <em>Re-visioning the Undefinable: A Generative Rhetorical Analysis of Trauma Narratives in Horror Films</em> (Indiana University, Indianapolis)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-7--heremeneutics">Panel 7- Heremeneutics</h3>
<h4 id="430pm-fh-310">4:30pm FH 310</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Christopher Michael Hansen</strong>  <em>Conjuring Seth: On Posthuman Creative Practice in The Seth Material</em>  (University of Buffalo)</li>
<li><strong>Ahmed Tahsin Shams</strong> <em>Thijs Biersteker’s Screen Eco-Art as Green Publishing Prototype in the Anthropocene</em>  (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>SaeHim Park</strong> <em>Boredom and Annoyance in Film The Pregnant Tree and the Goblin</em> (Xavier University of Louisiana)</li>
<li><strong>Sohrab Mirab</strong>  <em>History, Allegory, and Poetics of Dissent: Pre-Revolutionary Iranian Avant-grade Animations of CIDCA</em>  (Indiana University, Bloomington)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-8--interrogating-power-narratives">Panel 8- Interrogating Power Narratives</h3>
<h4 id="430pm-fh-210">4:30pm FH 210</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cole Nelson and Jamie Theophilos</strong>	<em>Countering Repression and narrative architects in the Stop Cop City Movement</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Jeff Moscaritolo</strong> <em>The Cooley Report, Orientalist Knowledge-Making, and Dunn Meadow</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Bryce Greene</strong>	<em>Revisiting Media Imperialism: The Enduring Relevance Of The Propaganda Model</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Caro Reed-Ferrara</strong>	<em>And You’re Going to Kill Him for Me”: Neoliberal Feminism and Hegemony in American National Security Media</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
