<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Common Ground 2025</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Common Ground 2025</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 17:05:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Speakers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 17:05:22 -0500</pubDate><author>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/friday/</guid>
      <description>Ramón Resendiz 1:30pm, Franklin Hall, Room 310
Dr. Ramón Resendiz is a Xicanx documentary media producer and visual anthropologist from the south Texas borderlands. His research interrogates the material and imaginary intersections of systemic violence, national borders, memory, visual culture, and settler colonialism. He investigates the erasure of Indigenous peoples and how modern nation states are visualized by archival institutions across the Texas/U.S. and northplacementern Mexico border landscapes, and the ways memory workers and cultural producers render these erasures visible.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="ramón-resendiz">Ramón Resendiz</h2>
<p><strong>1:30pm, Franklin Hall, Room 310</strong></p>
<p><img src="/images/Resendiz.jpg" alt="targets"></p>
<p><a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm7475396/bio/">Dr. Ramón Resendiz</a> is a Xicanx documentary media producer and visual anthropologist from the south Texas borderlands. His research interrogates the material and imaginary intersections of systemic violence, national borders, memory, visual culture, and settler colonialism. He investigates the erasure of Indigenous peoples and how modern nation states are visualized by archival institutions across the Texas/U.S. and northplacementern Mexico border landscapes, and the ways memory workers and cultural producers render these erasures visible.</p>
<p>He has produced multiple collaborative documentaries including, Voces del Norte: <em>Mariachi Quinto Sol de UW</em> (2016), <em>El Muro | The Wall</em> (2017), and <em>Migrant: A Reflection from Thundercloud</em> (2019). He holds a Ph.D. in Media, Culture, and Communication from New York University and is currently a Postdoctoral Research Fellow at the Center for Research on Race &amp; Society at Indiana University.</p>
<p><strong>Exhuming Archival Resistance: Memory, Media, and Cultural Production on the Margins of the U.S.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The U.S.-Mexico borderlands are among the most heavily militarized and politicized landscapes of the 21st century, mediated through digital, print, social, and mass media. Mainstream narratives often frame this region as a lawless frontier under perpetual threat from Latin American asylum seekers, constructing it as an ahistorical site of encounter that legitimizes the carceral realities faced by migrants in the U.S.
Drawing on over a decade of visual documentary fieldwork, Dr. Ramón Resendiz presents insights from his multimodal ethnographic research on the U.S.’s southern margins. As both theorist and media producer, he employs video and film to document the present while exhuming erased histories of violence, revealing the enduring coloniality of power embedded in the aestheticizing regimes of Texas, Mexico, and the American Southwest. His work highlights overlooked acts of resistance by subaltern communities, illuminating their role in shaping the modern borderlands.
This keynote examines the visual culture of settler colonial archival institutions in the Texas borderlands, alongside resistance histories enacted by Mexican, Indigenous, and Black communities. It explores how these histories are in/visibilized, under/documented, and reimagined across media, shaping everyday visual experiences in “The Lone Star State”—the unceded lands of Indigenous peoples systematically erased from Texas’s historical record. Ultimately, this talk envisions more just representations of past violence to establish frameworks for justice, reconciliation, and a more equitable future.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="cory-doctorow">Cory Doctorow</h2>
<p><strong>4pm, Franklin Hall, Room 310</strong> or <a href="https://iu.zoom.us/meeting/register/Potbwk7eTlyoeYwaZRr7rw">Link to zoom here</a></p>
<p><img src="/images/doctorowflyer.png" alt="targets"></p>
<p><a href="https://pluralistic.net/">Cory Doctorow</a> is a science fiction author, digital rights activist, and journalist. His most recent nonfiction book is <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/721311/the-internet-con-by-cory-doctorow/">The Internet Con: How to Seize The Means of Internet Computation</a> (2023) a Big Tech disassembly manual. He is also the author of <a href="https://chokepointcapitalism.com/">Chokepoint Capitalism</a> (with Rebecca Giblin) (2023), about creative labor markets and monopoly; <a href="https://craphound.com/category/destroy/">How to Destroy Surveillance Capitalism</a> (2020)</p>
<p>Cory Doctorow will keynote the Media School Graduate Association’s Common Ground conference, presenting on his concept of <em>enshittification.</em> Coined the “2023 Digital Word of the Year,” enshittification describes the process by which internet media platforms become simultaneously unusable and un-quittable.</p>
<p><em>Enshittification</em> swept through the digital world over the past decade, and it has only accelerated since, as everything - grocery stores, nursing agencies, even public schools - became digital services. The more digital something is, the more vulnerable it is to enshittification.<em>Enshittification</em> isn’t a force of nature. It’s not a historic inevitability. It’s the eminently foreseeable result of specific policy choices made by named individuals in living memory, after these individuals were warned that enshittification would ensue. Enshittification was a choice, not an accident.</p>
<p>The choices that led to enshittification are not graven in stone. They are just that - <em>choices</em>. We can choose otherwise. Indeed, we <em>must</em>, if we are to have an internet that is fit for purpose and can serve as the digital nervous system that we can use to coordinate our survival in a 21st century beset by genocide, ecological collapse, and economic chaos.</p>
<p>What policy choices can we make? What path can get us to those choices? How do we end the enshittocene and build a new, good internet?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friday Film Screening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/screenings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/screenings/</guid>
      <description>Friday&amp;rsquo;s film screening will be at 7pm in the Commons of Franklin Hall Dana Kirk, “Changelog,” (2024) Indiana University, Bloomington
Changelog explores the experience of growing up on the internet and its implications in navigating socialization offline. It’s about change and how the meaning of change changes when change is logged. It’s a template for others to project their own web histories onto. It’s a confrontation and reconciliation with fragmented identity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="fridays-film-screening-will-be-at-7pm-in-the-commons-of-franklin-hall">Friday&rsquo;s film screening will be at 7pm in the Commons of Franklin Hall</h3>
<p><strong>Dana Kirk</strong>, “Changelog,” (2024) <em>Indiana University, Bloomington</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Changelog explores the experience of growing up on the internet and its implications in navigating socialization offline. It’s about change and how the meaning of change changes when change is logged. It’s a template for others to project their own web histories onto. It’s a confrontation and reconciliation with fragmented identity. This is a story of someone trying to tell their story without wanting to really tell it. Someone who has best understood the self through documentation, further documenting the self, but not quite divulging.
Changelog’s composition is sometimes wonky and misaligned, refractive with information and reflections, edited with the impatient cuts of a Youtube vlog, accented by the palpable clacking of keyboard keys. Rather than simply emulate the chaos of the internet, I want the audience to feel what it feels like to exist online. There is chaos and there is also solitude and quiet and remnants of memory. All while keys click.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Jack Bassett</strong>, “Kuehnert Dairy” (2024) <em>Indiana University, Bloomington</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>In Fort Wayne, Indiana for the last 125 years, the Kuehnert Family has bottled endless memories and gallon after gallon of milk. Now a new generation of Kuehnert Dairy Farmers have taken over things and have added a direct cow-to-consumer means of enjoyment. Entitled: “The Milk House”, the family’s new venture provides milk lovers with calcium-protein-rich natural dairy creations sold on the site the milk came from. Milk, Cheese, Butter, Ice Cream, and more are made from Kuehnert cows. The fifth-generation owner: Andrew Kuehnert aims to continue to grow agritourism with his family farm through the Milk House. The Kuehnert’s and their 300-plus cows are bringing in visitors to see how their operation works and tasting the farm’s dairy creations. This dairy showcases hows to illustrate the moo-ving message of how hard work, passion, and reimagining a family tradition can keep a pillar business alive for the next generation.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Adam Ritchie Carroll</strong>, “Mundane” (2024) <em>Indiana University, Bloomington</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Is it a routine or mundanity? How does your daily life play out, how do you pass the time?</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Ruby Berin</strong>, “A Moment in Time” <em>Indiana University, Bloomington</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>My film, A Moment in Time, was made in the spring 2024 semester in my production practicum class. In this class, we were able to work with different communities/organizations around Indiana before the Eclipse in April 2024. I chose to work with the Indiana Forest Alliance, and they put on a 2-day viewing during the weekend of the eclipse at Yellowwood State Forest and at the Tibetan Mongolian Cultural Center. They paid homage to the state&rsquo;s beautiful and unique forest ecosystems with a time capsule dedication, live music, crafts, presentations, hikes, and food. Attached is a photo of funding with the Microgrant Awardees. <a href="https://rural.indiana.edu/focus/arts-culture/eclipse/eclipse-awardee-projects.html">link here for more information</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Michael Yang</strong>, “Snow Blindness” <em>School of the Art Institute of Chicago</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Snow Blindness is an interdisciplinary art installation and performance piece that explores themes of technology, self-expression, and intimacy. Drawing on the phenomenon of snow blindness—a condition where one’s vision is overwhelmed in environments lacking focal points—the project translates this concept into a metaphor for the disorienting effects of digital communication. By layering personal recordings, reactive lighting, and real-time video distortion, this installation examines the often incomplete or distorted expressions of self in intimate relationships, mediated through technology.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Holden Brown</strong>, “My Favorite Pair” (2024) <em>Indiana University, Bloomington</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>It is an easy-going video of friends and family&rsquo;s favorite pair of shoes that highlights individuality.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Ahmed Tahsin Shams</strong>, “Truth, Power, and Freedom” (2025)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This documentary film captures the journey of Eric, a young Ghana-born American artist, as he navigates the complexities of identity, belonging, and artistic expression in the USA. Blending mixed media—canvas painting, music video aesthetics, and line art animation—the film attempts a blend of immersiveness and, at the same time, the Brechtian V-effect in Eric’s evolving creative process. His brushstrokes breathe life into historical figures like Trayvon Martin, Tamir Rice, and Emmett Till, reimagining them through his art as voices that refuse to be silenced. As the camera follows Eric crafting a new painting, his reflections on community, memory, and resistance unfold, shaping not only his canvas but the very essence of his identity.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Weihong Zheng</strong>, “The Diagrams of Sheshan Observatory” <em>University of Washington, Seattle</em></p>
<p><strong>Brian Johnson</strong>, &ldquo;I Can&rsquo;t Stop&rdquo; (2024) <em>Indiana University, Bloomington</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Originally created for my fall semester Production Practicum, this film uses a combination of self-shot and found footage. I chose to make this short a personal essay about the constant pressure to push myself using motion as the driving force behind the scenes.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Panels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>commonground@gmail.com (commonground)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/saturday/</guid>
      <description>Panel 1: Media Meets Geography 10am FH 310 Anna Stamm Staying Afloat: TV Station Marketing Strategies (Indiana University, Bloomington) Drew Heiderscheidt Using GIS to Stretch Archival Collections: A Case Study from Colorado (Indiana University, Bloomington) Feng Yi Yin	Linguistic Politics, Hybridity, and Localization: The Making of Transnational Indigenous African Language Television (Temple University) Abu Mohammad Sakil Faizullah Exploring Bluetooth Adoption Among Marginalized Rural Young Adults in Bangladesh: A Study from the Margins (Univerity of Georgia, Atlanta) Panel 2: Media Practices &amp;amp; Praxis 10am FH 210 Ran Wei The Paradox of Narrating from the Margins: the Self-representations of Kamagasaki in Amateur Media (Washington University in St.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="panel-1-media-meets-geography">Panel 1: Media Meets Geography</h3>
<h4 id="10am-fh-310">10am FH 310</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Anna Stamm</strong> <em>Staying Afloat: TV Station Marketing Strategies</em>
(Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Drew Heiderscheidt</strong>   <em>Using GIS to Stretch Archival Collections: A Case Study from Colorado</em>
(Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Feng Yi Yin</strong>	 <em>Linguistic Politics, Hybridity, and Localization: The Making of Transnational Indigenous African Language Television</em>
(Temple University)</li>
<li><strong>Abu Mohammad Sakil Faizullah</strong> <em>Exploring Bluetooth Adoption Among Marginalized Rural Young Adults in Bangladesh: A Study from the Margins</em>
(Univerity of Georgia, Atlanta)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-2-media-practices--praxis">Panel 2: Media Practices &amp; Praxis</h3>
<h4 id="10am-fh-210">10am FH 210</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ran Wei</strong> <em>The Paradox of Narrating from the Margins: the Self-representations of Kamagasaki in Amateur Media</em>
(Washington University in St. Louis)</li>
<li><strong>Jenna Sears</strong> <em>Digital Creative Geographies: Intercultural Filmmaking as Affective Placemaking</em>
(Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Julia Longo</strong>	 <em>Journalistic documentaries as an emancipatory practice for adolescents: dialogues between communicative citizenship and media literacy</em>
(Temple University)</li>
<li><strong>Narmeen Ijaz</strong> <em>Ethics in Feminist Documentary: Implications of Class and Privilege in Sharmeen Obaid-Chinoy’s Films</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-3-black-media-experiences">Panel 3: Black Media Experiences</h3>
<h4 id="1130am-fh-310">11:30am FH 310</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Marilyn Facey</strong> <em>New Media and Cultural Production: An examination of new media technologies on news and music production culture in Jamaica</em> (University of Illinois, Chicago)</li>
<li><strong>Kristin Wells</strong>  <em>Mediated Histories of Collegiate Sporting Protests: A Digital Humanities Approach</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Fabiola D&rsquo;Angelo</strong>	<em>Lovers Rock and The Black Sensorium</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Omoleye Adeyemi</strong>	<em>The Shade Room—A Digital Third Space for Black Individuals</em> (Univeristy of Maryland, College Park)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-4-heremeneutics">Panel 4: Heremeneutics</h3>
<h4 id="1130am-fh-210">11:30am FH 210</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Christopher Michael Hansen</strong>  <em>Conjuring Seth: On Posthuman Creative Practice in The Seth Material</em>  (University of Buffalo)</li>
<li><strong>Ahmed Tahsin Shams</strong> <em>Thijs Biersteker’s Screen Eco-Art as Green Publishing Prototype in the Anthropocene</em>  (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>SaeHim Park</strong> <em>Immersivce Biohazards and VR Proximity</em> (Xavier University of Louisiana)</li>
<li><strong>Sohrab Mirab</strong>  <em>History, Allegory, and Poetics of Dissent: Pre-Revolutionary Iranian Avant-grade Animations of CIDCA</em>  (Indiana University, Bloomington)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-5-fan-power">Panel 5: Fan Power</h3>
<h4 id="315pm-fh-310">3:15pm FH 310</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Juntong Wu</strong> <em>Mediating Film Festival in Post-Pandemic China: Cinephiles and Grassroots Media</em> (Columbia University) <em>(on zoom)</em></li>
<li><strong>Selena Cotte</strong> <em>Video essays and fan historians as alternative academics: Considering Defunctland and other theme park studies.</em> (University of Illinois, Chicago)</li>
<li><strong>Aditya Sahasrabudhe</strong> <em>Investigating fan aggression as a reaction to mediated crowd behavior</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Marina Mecham</strong> <em>A film they did not want you to see”: Jamil X. T. Qubeka’s Of Good Report, Sexual Violence, and the Horror of Government Denial</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-6-rendering-media-visions">Panel 6: Rendering Media Visions</h3>
<h4 id="315pm-fh-210">3:15pm FH 210</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aileen Min</strong> <em>Digital Water and Generative Absence: Reimagining East Asian Aesthetics in Digital Art</em> (Columbia University)</li>
<li><strong>Ibrahim Odugbemi</strong> <em>Global South Cinemas in the Face of Neoliberal Capitalism: The Examples of Nigeria and South Korea</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Aanila Tarannum</strong> (<em>Reassessment of the Aura: Analyzing the Categories of AI-generated Images in Facebook&rsquo;s Algorithmic Landscape</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Janice Day</strong> <em>Re-visioning the Undefinable: A Generative Rhetorical Analysis of Trauma Narratives in Horror Films</em> (Indiana University, Indianapolis)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-7-structuring-environmental-feelings">Panel 7: Structuring Environmental Feelings</h3>
<h4 id="430pm-fh-310">4:30pm FH 310</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Juntao Yang</strong>  <em>Fault Lines and Echoing Strata: Attunement and Unsecurement through East Asia’s Earthquake-Media</em> &mdash; (Columbia University)</li>
<li><strong>Stanislav Menzelevskyi</strong>  <em>Staging Apocalypse: Chornobyl Cinema, Environmental Protest, and Eschatological Melodrama</em> &mdash; (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Priscilla Boateng</strong>  <em>Navigating Motherhood and Mental Health in Ghana: A Critical Discourse Analysis of Postpartum Depression on Facebook</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Shitemi Khamadi</strong> <em>Media Representation of Indigenous Communities in Environmental Court Cases: A Feminist Critical Discourse Analysis of Landmark Judgments in Africa</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)
 </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="panel-8-interrogating-power-narratives">Panel 8: Interrogating Power Narratives</h3>
<h4 id="430pm-fh-210">4:30pm FH 210</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cole Nelson and Jamie Theophilos</strong>	<em>Countering Repression and narrative architects in the Stop Cop City Movement</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Jeff Moscaritolo</strong> <em>The Cooley Report, Orientalist Knowledge-Making, and Dunn Meadow</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Bryce Greene</strong>	<em>Revisiting Media Imperialism: The Enduring Relevance Of The Propaganda Model</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
<li><strong>Caro Reed-Ferrara</strong>	<em>And You’re Going to Kill Him for Me”: Neoliberal Feminism and Hegemony in American National Security Media</em> (Indiana University, Bloomington)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
